# **Ashish Shah**

# Sales Manager

Father Name - Shashikant Shah

Address: C-108, Vishwas Park, Near - Tar Factory Chowk, Uttam Nagar, New Delhi - 110059

#### **Phone**

+91 8860014455

#### E-mail

## ashu.ashish2208@gmail.com

#### **Skills**

- > Flexible Team Player
- Relationship Builder
- Confident
- Keen Learner
- Finance
- New Business Development
- Review of contract

#### **Hobbies & Interests:**

- Travelling
- > Exploring different culture

# **Professional Summary:**

Performance-Oriented Sales Leader offering exceptional record of achievement over 10+ year's career.

Result-driven professional with significant and progressive experience for successfully managing all aspects of a customer contact center processes like establishing and monitoring productivity goals.

To acquire the professional skills and practical knowledge which can give optimum advantage to my professional experience to increase the profitability.

# **Work History**

Apr 2017 to March 2022 -: Sales Manager (New Car loan)

Rapid Global Business Solutions, Gurugram (Deployed to Ford Credit) (Aug 2016 to Apr 2017)

# (Ford Credit India Pvt. Ltd., Gurugram, Haryana)

- Handling Dealer Retails and wholesale business
- Team and Dealers management
- New Dealer Empanelment
- Grew retail sales volume in assigned territory above 30% penetration through strategic budgeting and product promotion
- Market Survey, Feasibility & competitors Report.
- Customer Services (Handling Allotment, Availability, Bank Finance and Presentations etc.)
- Organizing sales promotional activities to maximum.
- Update team and channels about new scheme and product time to time.
- Organize training for channels sales team about finance policy.
- Adheres to all company policies, procedures and business ethics codes and ensures that they are communicated and implemented within the team.
- To execute marketing events and promotions to generate the business
- Increased sales volume by expanding product line to new dealers, including Retail and Wholesale dealers.
- Support to wholesales team to provide the audit report within the timeline.
- Monitored sales team performance, analyzed sales data and reported information to Regional Sales Manager.

# Jul 2015 to Jun 2016: District Sales Manager (TWL loan)

# (Home Credit India Pvt. Ltd., Gurgaon)

Home Credit India is a leading consumer finance provider that offers easy, simple and fast loans for every dream and believes in making financial services simple, transparent and easily accessible to all.

My role and responsibility is to handling a team of the salespeople, set a target for the company's sale and goals, and prepare the weekly/monthly sales report, sales feedback and analysis the performance of sales person.

- To achieve well defined Sales Target and other Policies of the company.
- To visualize new strategies to achieve the task given by the company to my profile.
- To handle a dedicated team of Sales Associates, helping them in achieving their sales target, motivate them.
- To control Attrition rate of Sales Associates.
- Creation of new Business generating POS's.
- To control and handle delinquencies generated.
- To maintain a healthy Dealer to Company relationship

# Sep 2014 to Jun 2015: Sales Manager (New and Used Car loan)

# (Axis Securities Limited, New Delhi, Delhi)

- Identified, hired and trained highly qualified staff by teaching best practices, procedures and sales strategies.
- Identified opportunities for growth within NCR territory and collaborated with sales team to reach the sales goal.
- New Dealer Empanelment
- Achievement of sales targets and key performance indicators on activity, sales & persistency by developing, formulating and implementing specific sales plans to achieve targets.
- Proactive learning and self-development initiatives to understand the latest product offerings in the market.
- Monitored customer buying trends, Market conditions and competitor actions to adjust strategies and achieve sales goals.

# Oct 2011 to Sep 2014: Sales Executive (New Car loan)

### (MF Process and Solutions Pvt. Ltd. /Magma Fincorp Ltd.)

- In direct sales of new car, finance/handled dealers and DSA of Retail Finance.
- Increased sales volume by expanding product line to new dealers
- Targeted new dealers and increased sales 5 to 10% through proactive sales and negotiation technique.
- Built relationship with customers and community to establish long-term business growth.
- Maintained up-to-date knowledge of Auto Loan product/Schemes and performed competitor analysis.

# Nov 2008 to Sep 2011: Promoter

# (Reliance Communication, New Delhi)

- Handling Retail Sales (Connection, Data Card etc.).
- Promoting the brand and achieving the sales target.
- Good customer relationship.

#### Education

Academic Degree	College/Institute	Board/University	Year	Percentage
MA-History	Govt. Collage Dhamtari (C.G.)	Pt. Ravi Shankar Shukla University Raipur (C.G.)	2004	57%
B.AHistory	Govt. Collage Dhamtari (C.G.)	Pt. Ravi Shankar Shukla University Raipur (C.G.)	2002	45%
XII	Mennonite H.S. School Dhamtari (C.G.)	M.P. Board, Bhopal	1999	57%
X (SSC)	Mennonite H.S. School Dhamtari (C.G.)	M.P. Board, Bhopal	1997	48%

# **Awards and Achievement:**

- Achieved spot recognition awards from Ford Credit for doing 74 cases in the Month of Oct –
  2019. This is the highest number achieved by a dam across Pan India.
- Achieved more than 148% for the allocated Target in terms of units & Retail penetration
- 4 times received the top achiever certificate to maintain the highest penetration and supported to wholesales team also in conducting audits.

# **Declaration:**

I hereby declare that the facts given in resume are correct to best of my knowledge and belief.

[ASHISH SHAH]